# **ISAIAH LEACH**

petrichorwebdev@gmail.com portfolio (425) 229-9117 Inkedin.com/in/isaiah-petrichor/ pithub.com/IsaiahPetrichor Rend, OR

#### **SUMMARY**

Proven Software Development Engineer with over two years of experience specializing in C#, Javascript, React, Unit Testing, and Responsive Design. As a dedicated lifelong learner, I attended a 500+ hour coding boot camp where I learned industry best practices and application architecture. I then became part of Launch Consulting Group as a Software Development Engineer where I gained skills in C#, Azure Technologies, and Test Driven Development. My current project is for a Fortune 500 company making an internal application that produces business reports to increase productivity and reduce burnout.

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages: C#, Javascript, Typescript, SQL, HTML, CSS, Python, Java, JSON
- Libraries: React, Redux, Bcrypt, .NET, Pug
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, CosmosDB, SQL Server
- Testing: Mocha, Chai, NUnit, Jest, Selenium
- CI/CD: Azure, Azure DevOps, GIT, Heroku, Docker
- Other: Express.js, NodeJS, JWTs, Linux, ChatGPT, Azure Data Factory, Azure Databricks

### In a developer role at your company, I will...

- Code with clear communication, following company style guides.
- Write fully automated code tests in adherence to best practices.
- Leverage the current CICD pipeline in place or build new CICD pipelines from the ground up.
- Build responsive frontend designs to spec per the UX design.
- Build out API routes per RESTful design structure.
- Be supportive and accepting of constructive criticism.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Launch Consulting Group - Software Development Engineer**

Remote Dec 2022 - Present

- Developed on a team working for a Fortune 500 tech company on an internal application in a Scrum environment using Azure to expand and refine features while communicating progress and ideas with our stakeholders.
- Became cross-trained and proficient with Azure Technologies including Databricks, Data Factory, DevOps, Pipelines, Application Insights, App Services, Functions, ARM Templates, Bicep, and more, increasing value by at least 3 times.
- Grew skillset by working across the tech stack with non-Azure technologies such as Python, C#, Java, React, CSS, MySQL, FluentUI, ASP.Net, etc, improving knowledge and efficiency of the over 8 technologies listed.
- Collaborated on a 20+ person team to continue development on the React frontend of a large-scale production bids and management application for a large construction company with over 1,800 employees.
- Learned about general concepts, current limitations, ethical concerns, and practical use of AI in the workplace, and implementation of AI in specific tasks to increase productivity by 10x.

#### **Clearviction - Software Developer**

Remote Oct 2022 - March 2023

- Implemented 10+ new features and developed 25+ solutions to existing issues within our React web application.
- Contributed to an Agile team environment of over 15 people to perform asynchronous work while maintaining clear communication and expectations using Kanban boards.
- Clarified our dev needs to non-technical team members and ensured consistent expectations between teams and disciplines, reducing the time spent on pre-dev discussions by a factor of 3.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Petrichor Coffee**

**Remote** Mar 2022 - May 2022

- Created a React web application that interacts with the backend and database to provide a clean and easy-to-use consumer coffee distribution website.
- Designed a fast and responsive UI/UX to navigate with load times under 2 seconds on desktop devices.
- Addressed authentication and security concerns with JsonWebTokens, and the Bcrypt library.
- Deployed to the cloud using a CI/CD pipeline that builds in under 5 minutes, hosted on Render.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Codecademy - Full Stack Engineering | Front End Engineering

**Remote** Mar 2020 - Sep 2021

- Became proficient in practical software development standards focused on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, and Redux on the frontend, NodeJS, ExpressJS, SQL, Postgres, algorithms, and data structures on the backend.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks.
- Developed organized projects to support and implement my knowledge to exceed requirements without overengineering, following the KISS design principle.